# **PradeepRaj**

pradeeprajr93@gmail.com | +91 824 822 9854 | DOB: 21-Aug-1993 | Lives in Chennai

Online Portfolio link: https://pradeeprair93.github.io/portfolio/

#### About me:

Full stack developer and UX designer with more than 5 years of experience in Web application development, UX, and motion graphic design. To increase my areas of expertise and to stay relevant I learn constantly and continue to be a lifelong learner.

### **Work Experience:**

### Infosys

### Role: Specialist Programmer

Mar 2020 - Present

- Designed and developed a CRM platform for a market leading US based insurance client using technologies like Angular, NodeJS, NestJS
- Worked in an agile team and familiar using tools like JIRA, BitBucket
- Rated as "Exceeded expectations" during all my appraisal cycles till date

### Role: **Technology Analyst**

Jan 2017 – Feb 2020

- Designed and developed multiple full-fledged web applications from scratch by mentoring a team of four
  - Designed and developed a chatbot testing platform using Angular and Spring boot.
  - Designed and developed a sophisticated video personalization studio. It has options to add annotations on top of a video, rich timeline control options, ability to export entire configuration as JSON file, etc.
  - Designed and developed a rich video player with personalization options and filed a US patent for the same.
- Developed various portals, demo applications for our products with complex layouts
- Interacted directly with clients from US, UK and shared deliverables on time

# Role: Graphic, Motion and Web Designer

Feb 2016 – Jan 2017

- Designed product portals and studio prototypes using Adobe Illustrator and Photoshop
- Designed motion graphic videos based on client requirements
- Used Adobe After Effects for designing videos
- Videos have been designed and delivered within timeline with quality

# Role: Systems Engineer Trainee

Sep 2015 – Feb 2016

- Completed 6 months training at Infosys Global Training Centre, Mysore
- Trained in various technologies/tools like Python, Java, TIBCO and Web Technologies
- Completed the training with the High Performer badge

#### **Education:**

Bachelor of Electrical and Electronics Engineering Graduated: May 2015

(Mepco Schlenk Engineering College, Sivakasi) GPA - 8

Higher Secondary Education - 12th Grade Completed: March 2011

(Sri Vidya Mandir Matriculation School, Uthangarai) Percentage: 94.3%

### Tools and Technology:

Web: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Angular, NodeJS, Express, WebAssembly

Mobile: Progressive Web Apps (PWA), Flutter, Hybrid apps using NativeScript

Design: Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop, After Effects (with scripting), Axure, C4D Lite

Cloud: Microsoft Azure (VMs, Blob storage), Firebase, Dialogflow

## **Accomplishments and interests:**

- Filed two US patents in video personalization using web technologies
- Won a design hackathon conducted by **John Deere** on digitization category
- Taken webinars to wider audience on concepts like PWAs, WebAssembly, UI Design, etc.
- RISD (Rhode Island School of Design) Certified Strategic Designer
- Contribute to open source and develop personal projects (<a href="https://github.com/pradeeprajr93">https://github.com/pradeeprajr93</a>)
- Take up design challenges and post it to Dribbble (<a href="https://dribbble.com/pradeepraj">https://dribbble.com/pradeepraj</a>)
- Using my design skills, upload informative videos to YouTube (https://www.youtube.com/user/knowinminutes)
- Blog my thoughts on Medium (<a href="https://medium.com/@pradeeprajr93">https://medium.com/@pradeeprajr93</a>)
- Certified with BEC Vantage, Global English (Level 6)
- Undergone a course on Ethnographic research to understand users' psychology
- Love to take courses on platforms like Khan Academy, Coursera, Udacity and read books.

#### Self-declaration:

I hereby declare that all the above furnished information is true to my knowledge.

Place: Chennai Sincerely,

Date: 18-Nov-2020 PradeepRaj